<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Esteban Ramos | Skyhook Data Management</title><link>https://skyhookdm.github.io/author/esteban-ramos/</link><atom:link href="https://skyhookdm.github.io/author/esteban-ramos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Esteban Ramos</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://skyhookdm.github.io/author/esteban-ramos/avatar_hua4fb73c73635b1221a1356a6c61355cd_159285_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url><title>Esteban Ramos</title><link>https://skyhookdm.github.io/author/esteban-ramos/</link></image><item><title>Split gRPC: An Isolation Architecture for RPC Stacks on SmartNICs</title><link>https://skyhookdm.github.io/talks/20230817/esteban.ramos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://skyhookdm.github.io/talks/20230817/esteban.ramos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Remote procedure calls are a major contributor to performance variance in distributed systems due to lack of isolation and contention on shared resources. In this talk, I will introduce the novel architecture we built to address this problem, and cover our experience in implementing a prototype over gRPC with an emphasis on the communication layer between a host CPU and the SmartNIC. The basic idea is to partition RPC applications into two communicating components: one dedicated to user-implemented business logic, and one dedicated to RPC infrastructure processing. The infrastructure process can be run on a dedicated core or on a smart NIC (e.g., IPU or DPU), providing effective physical isolation and predictable performance. An evaluation of a proof-of-concept prototype shows that the split architecture adds modest overhead for average case latency, but allows for lower latency and and higher throughput under host CPU load.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>