<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Administrator | Skyhook Data Management</title><link>https://skyhookdm.github.io/author/administrator/</link><atom:link href="https://skyhookdm.github.io/author/administrator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Administrator</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://skyhookdm.github.io/author/administrator/avatar_hue97a424c08a82cf023f70665a2e52816_688399_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url><title>Administrator</title><link>https://skyhookdm.github.io/author/administrator/</link></image><item><title>CROSS, Skyhook, and Polyphy</title><link>https://skyhookdm.github.io/event/20230427/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://skyhookdm.github.io/event/20230427/</guid><description>&lt;p>We would like to invite you to a day-long hybrid workshop on April 27, 2023, entitled “CROSS, Skyhook, and Polyphy: Institutional support for creating Paths to Open Source Ecosystems for Open Source Products in Research.&amp;quot; This hybrid workshop will be held at UC Santa Cruz with remote access for participants unable to attend in-person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With support from an NSF Pathways to Enable Open Source Ecosystems (POSE) Phase 1 grant, the NSF Institute for Research and Innovation in Software for High-Energy Physics (IRIS-HEP), and the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, the goal of the workshop is to scope out self-sustaining ecosystems for the &lt;a href="https://github.com/skyhookdm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Skyhook&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://polyphy.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Polyphy&lt;/a> projects and to create an institutional model within the &lt;a href="https://cross.ucsc.edu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Center for Research in Open Source Software (CROSS)&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://skyhookdm.github.io/">Open Source Program Office (OSPO) UC Santa Cruz&lt;/a> to create paths to sustainable open source ecosystems for research products across UC campuses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A draft agenda for the event &lt;del>will be provided by March 27&lt;/del> is available &lt;a href="https://cross.ucsc.edu/news/news/20230427poseevent.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a> as well as a &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1znmoRvnmoZk1YMGWu7wIusC7KxlI6R_sSuXuK5PQ9LQ/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">white paper&lt;/a> that will form the basis for the day’s discussion. The workshop’s interactive sessions will discuss strategies for creating and sustaining institutional support for creating open source ecosystems, using
Skyhook and Polyphy as examples. We will also hear updates from our CROSS fellows about their research projects that are already creating open source products that likely will benefit from institutional support for open source ecosystems in the future.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>